<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homepages on Tue&#39;s Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://tuenguyen004.github.io/homepage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homepages on Tue&#39;s Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://tuenguyen004.github.io/homepage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://tuenguyen004.github.io/homepage/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tuenguyen004.github.io/homepage/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Did you know: Tue is pronounced as &amp;ldquo;two-aye&amp;rdquo;?
Hello, my name is Tue (2A). I&amp;rsquo;m a rising senior at Tufts University majoring in Mechanical Engineering. My skills and interests are in electromechnical design, product testing, and brain-computer interfaces.
Currently, I work at Bray Lab PALLS where I help Tufts&#39; students brainstorm and fabricate their most ambitious designs to life!
Check out all my projects in the section below or sorted by hardware, software, electronics, etc.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Did you know: Tue is pronounced as &amp;ldquo;two-aye&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, my name is &lt;code&gt;Tue (2A)&lt;/code&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m a rising senior at &lt;code&gt;Tufts University&lt;/code&gt; majoring in &lt;code&gt;Mechanical Engineering&lt;/code&gt;. My skills and interests are in electromechnical design, product testing, and brain-computer interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, I work at &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.tufts.edu/bray/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Bray Lab PALLS&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; where I help Tufts&#39; students brainstorm and fabricate their most ambitious designs to life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out all my projects in the section below or sorted by &lt;a href=&#34;https://tuenguyen004.github.io/tags/hardware&#34;&gt;hardware&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://tuenguyen004.github.io/tags/software&#34;&gt;software&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://tuenguyen004.github.io/tags/electronics/&#34;&gt;electronics&lt;/a&gt;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://tuenguyen004.github.io/homepage/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tuenguyen004.github.io/homepage/contact/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently seeking for full-time and/or internship positions for Spring and Summer 2023, but my inbox is OPEN for any opportunities. I&amp;rsquo;m always looking to be a part of something cool!
Feel free to reach out and say hello 👋
 Resume (in PDF): last updated on August 2022 Let&#39;s get in touch!: on Github, Linkedin, or via email  </description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently seeking for &lt;code&gt;full-time and/or internship positions for Spring and Summer 2023&lt;/code&gt;, but &lt;strong&gt;my inbox is OPEN for any opportunities&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m always looking to be a part of something cool!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to reach out and say hello 👋&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Resume (in PDF)&lt;/code&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1jBTHOz_wsk1-E2xdAwhxxsOVwY4u7iy_/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;last updated on August 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Let&#39;s get in touch!&lt;/code&gt;: on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tuenguyen004&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tue-hm-nguyen/&#34;&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt;, or via &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:tue.nguyen004@gmail.com&#34;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>https://tuenguyen004.github.io/homepage/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tuenguyen004.github.io/homepage/education/</guid>
      <description>Tufts University, School of Engineering B.S. Mechanical Engineering (minor in Computer Science) • Sep 2019 - May 2023
 Mechanics: Equilibrium FBD of static and dynamic particles and rigid bodies; stress and strain of static members under various loadings; kinematics and kinetics of bodies in 2D and 3D plane motion; momentum-impulse and work-energy theorems for dynamic systems   Engineering Design: Failure theories and safety criteria under loading conditions; FEA simulation and Castiliagno&amp;rsquo;s Theorem; introductory analysis of machine design elements; user-centric ideation and engineering decision-making; working with vendors and clients to communicate designs   Materials &amp;amp; Manufacturing: Principles identification/selection of materials and manufacturing processes; microstructures and properties characterization; mechanisms of structural modification and testing methods; CAD and engineering drawings of parts and assemblies   Thermal Fluid Systems: Application of thermodynamic reasoning to system design; classical fluid mechanics and heat transfer in various conditions; fluid properties and analysis of different systems and flows;   Electromechanical Systems: Design and analysis of PCB and electrical components; use of sensors, feedback controllers, and actuators for hardware implementation; oscilloscopes and computer tools to test and debug circuits; modeling and control of dynamic systems    Robotics: Introduction to controls, image processing, sensor development, filtering, and state machines; basic concepts from circuit theory, artificial intelligence, microprocessor control and physical design used in basic robotics competition</description>
      <content>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tufts-university-school-of-engineering&#34;&gt;Tufts University, School of Engineering&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B.S. Mechanical Engineering (minor in Computer Science) • Sep 2019 - May 2023&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Mechanics&lt;/code&gt;: Equilibrium FBD of static and dynamic particles and rigid bodies; stress and strain of static members under various loadings; kinematics and kinetics of bodies in 2D and 3D plane motion; momentum-impulse and work-energy theorems for dynamic systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Engineering Design&lt;/code&gt;: Failure theories and safety criteria under loading conditions; FEA simulation and Castiliagno&amp;rsquo;s Theorem; introductory analysis of machine design elements; user-centric ideation and engineering decision-making; working with vendors and clients to communicate designs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Materials &amp;amp; Manufacturing&lt;/code&gt;: Principles identification/selection of materials and manufacturing processes; microstructures and properties characterization; mechanisms of structural modification and testing methods; CAD and engineering drawings of parts and assemblies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Thermal Fluid Systems&lt;/code&gt;: Application of thermodynamic reasoning to system design; classical fluid mechanics and heat transfer in various conditions; fluid properties and analysis of different systems and flows;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Electromechanical Systems&lt;/code&gt;: Design and analysis of PCB and electrical components; use of sensors, feedback controllers, and actuators for hardware implementation; oscilloscopes and computer tools to test and debug circuits; modeling and control of dynamic systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Robotics&lt;/code&gt;: Introduction to controls, image processing, sensor development, filtering, and state machines; basic concepts from circuit theory, artificial intelligence, microprocessor control and physical design used in basic robotics competition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Computer Science&lt;/code&gt;: Data structures and algorithms in C++ such as linked lists, trees, graphs, dynamic storage allocation, and recursion; machine-level concepts in C and assembly code including memory, cache, registers, machine arithmetic, and bitwise operations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Senior Design Project&lt;/code&gt;: To Be Updated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>who&#39;s 2A</title>
      <link>https://tuenguyen004.github.io/homepage/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tuenguyen004.github.io/homepage/about/</guid>
      <description>2A (noun.)
2A, or Tue as his real first name and pronounced as &amp;quot;two-aye&amp;quot; for ease of communication, is the creator of this portfolio.
:::::::::::::::::::: a bit more about 2A ::::::::::::::::::::
I design robust and intuitive electromechanical systems!
From three-pound BattleBots to a soft-robotics exoskeleton, I&amp;rsquo;m experienced in both working from scratch and modifying existed technology to create functional prototypes. Familiar with various aspects of robotics and fabrication methods, I can then turn them into dynamic and responsive systems.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2A (noun.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2A, or &lt;code&gt;Tue as his real first name&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;pronounced as &amp;quot;two-aye&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt; for ease of communication, is the creator of this portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:::::::::::::::::::: &lt;em&gt;a bit more about 2A&lt;/em&gt; ::::::::::::::::::::&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I design robust and intuitive &lt;a href=&#34;https://tuenguyen004.github.io/tags/hardware/&#34;&gt;electromechanical&lt;/a&gt; systems!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From three-pound BattleBots to a soft-robotics exoskeleton, I&amp;rsquo;m experienced in both working from scratch and modifying existed technology to create functional prototypes. Familiar with various aspects of &lt;a href=&#34;https://tuenguyen004.github.io/tags/robotics/&#34;&gt;robotics&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://tuenguyen004.github.io/tags/fabrication/&#34;&gt;fabrication&lt;/a&gt; methods, I can then turn them into dynamic and responsive systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I&amp;rsquo;m not afraid to dabble in &lt;a href=&#34;https://tuenguyen004.github.io/tags/software&#34;&gt;software&lt;/a&gt;, having written code that controls hardware prototypes and even devised a mathematical model with biometric datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of hardware engineering, I love &lt;a href=&#34;https://tuenguyen004.github.io/tags/3d-design&#34;&gt;sketching and 3D modeling&lt;/a&gt; anything I can touch and imagine. I also educate others how to do the same, &lt;a href=&#34;https://tuenguyen004.github.io/tags/teaching/&#34;&gt;teaching K-12 students&lt;/a&gt; how to bring their project ideas into reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my free time, I can be found modifying my &lt;a href=&#34;https://tuenguyen004.github.io/tags/ender3pro/&#34;&gt;Ender3Pro&lt;/a&gt; or playing board games with friends!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about solving problems through engineering and design. To me, the combination of purposeful craftsmanship and efficient workflow has the power to make the world a much better place. The opportunity to make that come to true one day is what drives me to wake up, learn, and create everyday!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
